A Guide to the WRVA Radio Collection, 1925-2000
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Collection, 1925-2000
Library of Virginia
38210
ca. 52 cubic feet, 637 compact discs, and 1,760 cassette tapes
WRVA Radio
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Clear Channel Communications, June 2001.
Biographical/Historical Information
WRVA was officially dedicated on 2 November 1925. Owned and operated by Larus & Brother Company, manufacturers of Edgeworth Smoking Tobacco and other tobacco products, the station initially operated as a community station without commercial revenue and broadcast only two evenings a week. The Corn Cob Pipe Club was one of the many regular programs begun in 1925. It proved so popular with listeners throughout the United States and Canada that by July 1935, almost nine hundred clubs were established in the United States and foreign countries. By January 1926, the station increased its schedule to three nights a week, and by 1929, WRVA was broadcasting day and night seven days a week. Also in 1929, the station increased its power from 1,000 watts to 5,000 watts and became affiliated with the National Broadcasting Company (NBC). In May 1933, WRVA opened new broadcasting studios in the Hotel Richmond, on 9th and Grace Streets. In April 1935, the station built and began using the first all-wood self-supporting radio tower in America. On 27 June 1937, WRVA joined Columbia Broadcasting Systems (CBS) as a full time affiliate. On 17 March 1939, the 50,000 watt transmitter, located in eastern Henrico County was officially dedicated. In March 1940, Sunshine Sue and Her Rangers first broadcast on WRVA. In September 1946, WRVA leased the old Lyric Theater on 9th and Broad Street and the Old Dominion Barn Dance began airing on WRVA. On 28 January 1959, WRVA rejoined NBC. On 29 May 1968, the new WRVA studio, located in historic Church Hill and overlooking Richmond, was dedicated.
In 1968, Larus & Brother Company reorganized and became the Larus Investing Company. In July 1968, WRVA AM and FM became WRVA Radio, Inc. and WRVA-FM Radio, Inc., respectively, subsidiary corporations of the Larus Investing Company. Larus Investing Company sold its entire WRVA stock to Southern Broadcasting Company of Winston, Salem, North Carolina in November 1969. In August 1977, Harte-Hanks Newspapers, Inc., purchased Southern Broadcasting Company, including WRVA-AM and WRVQ-FM. Harte-Hanks Communications, Inc., sold the radio stations to Edens Broadcasting Company, a company formed by the senior managers of Harte- Hanks Radio, Inc., a subsidiary of Harte-Hanks Communications, Inc., in December 1984. In September 1991, WRVA was sold to Force II Communication, L. P., of San Diego. In the Spring 1992, Clear Channel Communications bought WRVA and is the current owner.
Scope and Content Information
The WRVA Radio Collection spans seventy-five years and contains applause letters, minutes, anniversary booklets, program scripts, program guides, newsletters, histories, interviews, employee questionnaires, sales manuals, audience and sales promotions, rate cards, listener surveys, posters, newspaper clippings, FCC applications and reports, drawings, photographs, and sound recordings. This material documents the history of WRVA, the role the station played in Virginia and Richmond for over half-a-century, and the development of radio in Virginia and the United States. The collection is also rich in material on the Larus & Brother Company, including histories, anniversary booklets, photographs of officials, employees, and factories, and promotions.
The sound recordings date from the 1930's to the 1990's and contain news broadcasts of significant local, state, national, and world events and personalities, programs of a local and regional interest, including the Capitol Squirrel, Calling All Cooks, the Radio Scholarship Quiz, and the Quiz of Two Cities, and musical programs, such as the Corn Cob Pipe Club, the Old Dominion Barn Dance, the Sunshine Hour, and the Silver Star Quartet. Selected sound recordings are now available for use on CD. Each CD has been cataloged individually. Search The Library of Virginia Archives and Manuscripts Catalog to find WRVA sound recordings of interest.
Records and audio/visual materials gathered by Debbie J. Ashley, WRVA Office Manager (retired).
Organization
Organized into the following series:
I. Correspondence, 1926-1991
II. Minutes, 1956-1978
III. Administrative Files
IV. Sales
V. WRVA Radio Dialog, 1938-1963
VI. New Building (1968), 1963-1969
VII. Subject Files
VIII. Publications
IX. Photographs, 1925-2000
X. Artifacts
XI. Sound Recordings
XII. Films and Videos
XIII. News Tape Morgue
XIV. Special Programs and Airchecks, 1981-1994
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1926-1991, 9 folders. (Box 1)
  The applause memos contain comments from listeners on the station's programming and document the strength of WRVA's signal. The geographical distribution of applause letters received reveals that WRVA had listeners from the Atlantic Provinces of Canada to California. The correspondence file includes letters, memos, and telegrams regarding matters relating to the running of the station, station policy, the hiring and promotion of employees, and listener responses to programming. Correspondence also documents the transfer of part of WRVA's archives to the University of Virginia. The public service correspondence includes letters from listeners commenting and/or expressing thanks for WRVA programming. In many cases, a response from WRVA is included.
  - Applause Memos, 1926 (Geographic Distribution of Applause Memos, 1929) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1933-1991 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence re. the University of Virginia's solicitation and acquisition of WRVA Archives, June-Aug. 1969 (Box 1)
  - Public Service, Jan. - Apr. 1966 (Box 1)
  - Public Service, May - Dec. 1966 (Box 1)
  - Public Service, 24 Apr. 1968, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Public Service, Jan.-May 1970 (Box 1)
  - Public Service, June-July 1970 (Box 1)
  - Public Service, Aug. 1970 - Jan. 1971 (Box 1)
- Series II: Minutes, 1956-1978, 11 folders. (Box 1)
  Includes minute books from WRVA Radio, Inc. and WRVA-FM, Inc., the subsidiary companies of the Larus Investing Company, the company formed when Larus and Brother Company reorganized in 1968. Also includes miscellaneous minutes and reports of staff, managers, and stockholders from 1956-1968
  - WRVA Radio, Inc. Minute Book, No. 1 - Charter (Box 1)
  - WRVA Radio, Inc. Minute Book, No. 1 - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1968-1970 (Box 1)
  - WRVA Radio, Inc. Minute Book, No. 1 - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1972-1978 (Box 1)
  - WRVA Radio, Inc. Minute Book, No. 1 - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - WRVA Radio, Inc. Minute Book, No. 1 - Stockholders Meeting Minutes, 1968-1977 (Box 1)
  - WRVA Radio, Inc. Minute Book, No. 1 - By-laws (Box 1)
  - WRVA-FM, Inc. Minute Book - Charter (Box 1)
  - WRVA-FM, Inc. Minute Book - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - WRVA-FM, Inc. Minute Book - Directors Meeting Minutes, 1968-1972 (Box 1)
  - WRVA-FM, Inc. Minute Book - Stockholders Meeting Minutes, 1968-1972 (Box 1)
  - Staff, Managers, and Stockholders Meeting Minutes and Reports, 1956-1968 (Box 1)
- Series III: Administrative Files (Box 2-6)
  Includes the files relating to the administrative functions of WRVA, including incorporation files, deeds, accounts receivable, FCC renewal applications, and employee benefits.
  Organized into the following four subseries: A. Ownership Records; B. Financial Records; C. Federal Communications Commission, (FCC), 1947-1969; D. Human Resources.
  - Subseries A: Ownership Records, 15 folders. (Box 2)
    Includes files relating to incorporation of WRVA after the creation of the Larus Investing Company, by-laws of WRVA Radio, Inc., the sale of WRVA to the Southern Broadcasting Company, and land deed titles to the transmitter and studio properties.
    - Larus Inventing Company - Amendments to Articles of Incorporation (Box 2)
    - Agreement of Sales, June 1968 (Box 2)
    - WRVA-AM - Charter and Filing (5 folders) (Box 2)
    - WRVA-FM - Charter and Filing, 1968 (Box 2)
    - WRVA Radio, Inc. - By-laws, 11 June 1968 (2 copies) (Box 2)
    - Southern Broadcasting Corporation (2 folders) (Box 2)
    - WRVA Radio Inc. Sale to Southern Broadcasting Company, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
    - Land Deed Titles to WRVA Transmitter and Studio Property, 1938-1978 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Subseries B: Financial Records, 7 folders. (Box 3)
    Includes accounts receivable and commissions for advertising sales.
    - Accounts Receivable - Cleanup Reports, Feb. 1983 - Jan. 1984 (6 folders) (Box 3)
    - Eastman Radio Commissions, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Subseries C: Federal Communications Commission (FCC), 1947-1969, 30 folders. (Box 3-5)
    Includes agreements, affidavits, and statements of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) Station Representative hearings from 1947-1949 regarding national spot sales, and FCC license renewal applications and ownerships reports from 1963-1969. These license renewal applications and ownership reports contain stockholder information, the percentage of air time devoted to entertainment, religious, news, agricultural, and educational programs, brief summaries of programs broadcasted, copies of unsolicited commendation and response letters to public service programming, and program and transmitter logs.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Station Representatives Hearing, 1947-1949 (2 folders) (Box 3)
    - License Renewal Applications and Ownership Reports, 1963 (6 folders) (Box 3)
    - License Renewal Applications and Ownership Reports, 1965 (3 folders) (Box 4)
    - License Renewal Applications and Ownership Reports, 1966 (11 folders) (Box 4-5)
    - License Renewal Applications and Ownership Reports, 1967 (Box 5)
    - License Renewal Applications and Ownership Reports, 1968 (Box 5)
    - License Renewal Applications and Ownership Reports, 1969 (5 folders) (Box 5)
    - FM Broadcast Station Construction Permit Application (FCC Form 319) (Box 5)
  - Subseries D: Human Resources, 13 folders. (Box 5-6)
    Includes material relating to employee benefits such as medical, insurance, and pension plans. Material of a sensitive nature has been removed and is restricted.
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - Bonus Computation, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Edens Broadcasting, Inc. - Aetna Insurance, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Group Insurance Program Enrollment Forms (Box 5)
    - Harte-Hanks / Aetna Monthly Premium Statement, 1984 (Box 5)
    - Harte-Hanks Communications, Inc. - Medical/Dental/Life Insurance Program Manual, 1979 (Box 5)
    - Liberty Mutual Automobile Insurance Accident Report Forms (Box 5)
    - Medical Conversion Benefits (Box 5)
    - Schedule of Insurance - WRVA Radio, Inc. and Larus & Brother Company, 1968 (Box 6)
    - Summary Annual Report for American Home Assurance Company Group AD & D Plan 19 Jan. 1984 (Box 6)
    - Summary Annual Report for Harte-Hanks Employee Benefit Plan, 6 Feb. 1984 (Box 6)
    - WRVA Employee Pension Plan (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Worker's Compensation (Employee Injury) - Liberty Mutual Insurance (Box 6)
- Series IV: Sales, 121 folders (Box 6-10)
  Contains material used and created by the WRVA Sales Department to attract advertisers, including manuals, advertisements, advertising booklets and displays, client presentations, newsletters, rate cards, and surveys. The advertisements, booklets, and displays were created to convey the listening power of WRVA and the benefits advertisers would received from advertising on the radio. The surveys contain information on the habits and preferences of WRVA's listening audience. The rate cards span from the 1930's to the 1960's and illustrate the costs of advertising on the radio. Also includes copies of WRVAds from 1950 to 1953, the sales department newsletter, which contained information on programming.
  Arranged alphabetically
  - Advertising - Memos, Announcements, Newsletters, Rates, Apr. 1955 - Apr. 1965 (2 folders) (Box 6)
  - Advertising, Mail Order - Plan of Future Development, Mar. 1951 (Box 6)
  - Advertisement - "Flip Over to AM. WRVA Live Radio 1140.", 1991 (Box 6)
  - Advertisement - "Thank You, Richmond For the Highest Average Rating of Any Radio Station in the U.S.!", 1948 (Box 6)
  - Advertisement - "This Size Ad" (Box 6)
  - Advertisement - "Top Winners - morning - noon - night", ca. 1957 (Box 6)
  - Advertisement - "Twenty-nine of the thirty top radio programs are all on WRVA-Radio", 1955 (Box 6)
  - Advertisement - "Want to deal yourself a winning hand with Richmond's blue chip listening audience?" (Box 6)
  - Advertisement - "Want to get really close to her?" (Box 6)
  - Advertisement - "WRVA's Extra Step Means Extra Sales For You", 1950 (Box 6)
  - Advertisement - "WRVA-Radio 'Tops Them'", 1957 (Box 6)
  - Advertisement Booklet - "A Comparison of Radio and Newspaper Efficiency in Virginia", 1952 (Box 6)
  - Advertisement Booklet - "does your advertising stop here? Richmond City Limits" ca. 1958 (Box 6)
  - Advertisement Booklet - "Figures and Figures, or statistics in one easy lesson" (Box 6)
  - Advertisement Booklet - "Is There A $1,704,000,000 Hole In Your Marketing Map?", ca. 1971 (Box 6)
  - Advertisement Booklet - "No Cellophane No Pink Ribbon (WRVA Radio promotion through newspapers, billboards, displays, etc.) (Box 6)
  - Advertisement Booklet - Norfolk and Tidewater Region, ca. 1938 (Box 6)
  - Advertisement Booklet - "Richmond - Growth Area of the South", ca. 1961 (Box 6)
  - Advertisement Booklet - "A Tale of Two Cities" (Box 6)
  - Advertisement Booklet - "The Total Coverage Radio Station in Richmond, Virginia", 1965 (Box 6)
  - Advertisement Booklet - "Unlock Your Sales Potential" (Box 7)
  - Advertisement Booklet - "WRVA #1 All Day", 1965 (Box 7)
  - Advertisement Booklet - "WRVA-Radio Unlocks More Virginia Homes", 1961 (Box 7)
  - Advertisement Display - "Unlock Your Sales Potential" (Box 7)
  - Advertisement Packet, 1965-1966 (Box 7)
  - Advertisements appearing in "Sponsor" (Box 7)
  - BMB Audience Study No. 1 - "Try This On Your Slide Rule!", 1946 (Box 7)
  - BMB Station Audience Map for WRVA - Nighttime, 1946 (Box 7)
  - BMB Station Audience Map for WRVA - Day and Night, Mar. 1949 (Box 7)
  - BMB Station Audience Report Study No. 2, Spring 1949 (Box 7)
  - CBS Listening Area - Richmond and Norfolk, 1944 (Box 7)
  - Circulation Report on Virginia's "Rich-urbia," 1964 (Box 7)
  - Client Presentation - VEPCO, ca. 1940s (Box 7)
  - Client Presentation - "A Proposal for Richmond, Fredericksburg & Potomac Railroad," 1952 (Box 7)
  - Coverage Maps (Box 7)
  - Listener Diary Study, Spring 1948 (3 folders) (Box 7)
  - Listener Diary Study, Spring 1948 - duplicate copy (3 folders) (Box 8)
  - Mailing Piece - "Wetherill Paint Letters," 1953 (Box 8)
  - Mailing Piece - "WRVA is the leading station in Richmond and #2 station in Norfolk," 1953 (Box 8)
  - Market Report - "An Analysis of Agricultural Market News Dissemination in Virginia," 1960 (Box 8)
  - Market Report - "WRVA Three-Way Radio," ca. 1966 (Box 8)
  - Nielson Service Coverage Report, 1961 (Box 8)
  - Norfolk Pulse, Summary of, Oct. - Nov. 1950 (Box 8)
  - Rate Cards, 1930's - 1968 (21 folders) (Box 8)
  - Rate Card and Data / Contract Form Information, 1936-1952, n.d. (4 folders) (Box 8-9)
  - Rate Card Forms (American Association of Advertising Agencies), 1960 (Box 9)
  - Rates - Miscellaneous, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Ratings of Richmond and Norfolk Stations, 1948 (Box 9)
  - Research - Richmond Market Area, 1959 (Box 9)
  - Research Report - "Reaching All Your Potential Market", ca. 1953 (Box 9)
  - Research Report - "The Richmond Radio Audience: A Profile", 1965 (Box 9)
  - Research Report - "WRVA-RADIO reaches a rich 72-country market" (Box 9)
  - Richmond Pulse Reports, Jan. 1953 - Feb. 1954 (Box 9)
  - Richmond Pulse, Summary of, July 1950 - June 1951 (Box 9)
  - Sales Department Reorganization, 1952 (Box 9)
  - Sales Manual, 1940's and 1950's (2 folders) (Box 9)
  - Sales Manual, 1950's (3 folders) (Box 9)
  - Sales Manual, 1950's and 1960's (4 folders) (Box 9)
  - Sales Manual - Miscellaneous, 1950's (Box 9)
  - Sales / Production Forms
  - Sales Promotion - WRVA/WRVQ, ca. 1986 (Box 10)
  - Sales Promotion Packet, 1972-1973 (Box 10)
  - Sales Promotion Packets, n.d. (Box 10)
  - Sales Promotion Poster - "WRVA Radio's 65 County Coverage Makes Richmond the 13th Biggest Buy in the Country" (Box 10)
  - Sales Questionnaire, 1945 (Box 10)
  - Shows Available on WRVA (used for client presentations), Aug. 1944 - Sept. 1947 (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Survey - "Adult Radio Audience", Feb. - Mar. 1963 (Box 10)
  - Survey - "Fifty-One out of Fifty-Five or How Good Can You Get!", 15 Feb. 1952 (Box 10)
  - Survey - Graphic Comparison, Richmond Radio Stations, Total Service Areas, N. C. S. No. 2, 1956 (Box 10)
  - Survey - "households reached by radio and television in metropolitan richmond", June 1956 (Box 10)
  - Survey - "households reached by radio and television in metropolitan richmond", June 1957 (Box 10)
  - Survey - Norfolk Listener Distribution, 21-27 Apr. 1940 (Box 10)
  - Survey - "The Pulse of Norfolk, Vol. I, No. 1," Oct. - Nov. 1950 (Box 10)
  - Survey - "The Pulse of Norfolk, Vol. II, No. 1," Dec. 1952 - Jan. 1953 (Box 10)
  - Survey - "The Pulse of Norfolk," Mar. 1952 (Box 10)
  - Survey - Richmond Listener Distribution, 10-16 Nov. 1940 (Box 10)
  - Survey - "Richmond, Va. Continuing Measurement of Radio Listening," May-Sept. 1945 (Box 10)
  - Survey - "Smoking and Listening Habits of University of Richmond Students" (Box 10)
  - Survey - Standard Audit & Measurement Services, Inc. Station Audience Report, Spring 1952 (Box 10)
  - Survey - State Planters, 1963 (Box 10)
  - Survey - Verifak Surveys Report in Richmond, Virginia, Jan. 1958 (Box 10)
  - Survey - "WRVA - The 50,000 Watt Voice of Virginia" (source: April-June 1967 Pulse for Richmond), 1967 (Box 10)
  - The Virginia Farmer and Market News, Sept. 1955 (Box 10)
  - WRVAds, Sept./Oct. 1950, Apr./May - Oct./Nov. 1951, Jan./Feb. 1952, Oct./Nov. 1953 (Box 10)
  - WRVA Daytime-Nighttime Coverage Map, ca. 1950's (Box 10)
  - WRVA-Radio Market Guide, ca. 1957 (Box 10)
  - WRVA Surveys, Mar. 1950 (Box 10)
- Series V: WRVA Radio Dialog, 1938-1963, 47 folders (Box 11-12)
  WRVA Dialog was the program guide for national and local programs airing on WRVA Radio. The guides included highlights of programs, time listings, and numerous photographs. Unfortunately, several significant gaps exist.
  - Inventory of Existing Dialogs (Box 11)
  - July 1938 (Box 11)
  - March, Sept. - Nov. 1939 (Box 11)
  - July - Aug., Dec. 1940 (Box 11)
  - June - July, Oct. - Dec. 1941 (Box 11)
  - Feb., June, Nov. - Dec. 1942 (Box 11)
  - July, Sept., Dec., 1943 (Box 11)
  - Jan. - Mar., May - Aug. 1944 (Box 11)
  - Sept. - Dec. 1944 (Box 11)
  - Feb. - Apr. 1945 (Box 11)
  - May - July 1945 (Box 11)
  - Aug. - Oct. 1945 (Box 11)
  - Nov. - Dec. 1945 (Box 11)
  - Jan. - Mar. 1946 (Box 11)
  - Apr. - June 1946 (Box 11)
  - July - Sept. 1946 (Box 11)
  - Oct. - Dec. 1946 (Box 11)
  - Jan., Apr. - May 1947 (Box 11)
  - June - Sept. 1947 (Box 11)
  - Oct. - Dec. 1947 (Box 11)
  - Jan. - Mar. 1948 (Box 11)
  - Apr. - June 1948 (Box 11)
  - July - Sept. 1948 (Box 12)
  - Oct. - Dec. 1948 (Box 12)
  - Jan. - Mar. 1949 (Box 12)
  - Apr. - June 1949 (Box 12)
  - July - Sept. 1949 (Box 12)
  - Oct.-Dec. 1949 (Box 12)
  - Jan. - Mar. 1950 (Box 12)
  - Apr. - June 1950 (Box 12)
  - July - Sept. 1950 (Box 12)
  - Oct. - Dec. 1950 (Box 12)
  - Jan. - Mar. 1951 (Box 12)
  - Apr. - June 1951 (Box 12)
  - Sept. - Dec. 1951 (Box 12)
  - Jan. - May, Sept., Nov. 1952 (Box 12)
  - Jan. - Mar. 1953 (Box 12)
  - Apr. - May 1953 (Box 12)
  - Oct. - Nov. 1953 (Box 12)
  - Jan. - Feb., Apr. 1954 (Box 12)
  - Sept. - Dec. 1954 (Box 12)
  - Jan. - Feb. 1955 (Box 12)
  - May, Sept. 1955 (Box 12)
  - Oct. - Dec. 1955 (Box 12)
  - Jan. - Apr. 1956 (Box 12)
  - 15 July 1963; 25 Oct. 1963 (Box 12)
  - Incomplete copies, n.d. (Box 12)
- Series VI: New Building (1968), 1963-1969, 30 folders and 1 card index box. (Box 13-15)
  Includes files relating to the planning, construction, and dedication of WRVA's new building on Church Hill, such architectural plans and surveys, construction specifications, invitations and RSVP's for the dedication, and the dedicatory remarks of then Governor Mills E. Godwin, Jr. Philip Johnson, a renowned architect, designed the building, which was dedicated in 1968.
  - Memos and Correspondence, Nov. 1963 - May 1968 (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Congratulatory Letters, 8 May - 27 June 1968 (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Letters of Regret, May 1968 (Box 13)
  - Architectural Drawings and Surveys
  - Architectural Record, Dec. 1969 (see page 96) (Box 13)
  - Clippings, 1966-1968 (Box 13)
  - Construction Specifications, 1967 (3 folders) (Box 13)
  - Crystal Set (Box 13)
  - Dedication Brochure (Box 13)
  - Dedication Mailing Lists (Box 13)
  - Dedication Receipts and Expenses (Box 13)
  - Dedication Remark of Gov. Mills E. Godwin, Jr., 29 May 1968 (Box 13)
  - Floor Plans (Box 13)
  - Philip Johnson, Architect (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous (publicity plan, dedication plan, notes, flowers, equipment) (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous (signage and mail delivery) (Box 14)
  - New Studio Proposals (Box 14)
  - Open House (Box 14)
  - Poster - "WRVA-Radio Moves Up!" (Box 14)
  - Press Packet (Box 14)
  - Press Releases, 1966-1968 (Box 14)
  - Production of Dedication Brochure and Invitations (Box 14)
  - Rough Drafts of Dedication Brochure Text (Box 14)
  - RSVP's, Invitations, Brochures, Envelopes (Box 14)
  - Script - WRVA-Radio Dedication Service, 29 May 1968 (Box 14)
  - "Search for status in station design," Broadcasting,26 May 1968 (Box 14)
  - Returned, Stamped, and Blank RSVP's (Box 15)
- Series VII: Subject Files (Box 16-31)
  This series contains advertisements, biographies, booklets, books, brochures, editorials, employee questionnaires, histories, interviews, letters, memorandums, memoirs, newsletters, newspaper clippings, posters, press releases, program guides, programs, promotions, scrapbooks, scripts, and speeches relating to the station's history, the Larus & Brother Company, the many individuals and staff who worked for WRVA, important events and individuals of the twentieth century, and radio programs and commercials. Of note are the files relating to WRVA's many anniversaries; the station's studios and transmitters; announcers, such as Alden Aaroe, Lou Dean, Wayne Lemon, Tim Timberlake, and Big John Trimble; staff, such as Walter R. Bishop, Ted Chezik, Bertha Hewlett, Calvin T. Lucy, Bill McGowan, John Tansey, and Harry Wood; performers, such as J. Robert Beadles, Pat Binford, Homer & Jethro, the Silver Star Quartet, Sunshine Sue, and Holland R. Wilkinson; special characters such as Millard the Mallard; musical programs, such as the Corn Cob Pipe Club, the Sunshine Hour, the Old Dominion Barn Dance, and the New Dominion Barn Dance; public service activities; local, state, and national politics and politicians; publicity and promotions; radio programs, such as Calling All Cooks, the Carl Stutz Show, and the Sports Desk with Bob Smith; and other radio stations, such as WBAZ, WBBL, and WCOD.
  - 20th Anniversary - Booklet and Chronology (Box 16)
  - 22nd Anniversary (Box 16)
  - 25th Anniversary - Booklet (Box 16)
  - 25th Anniversary - Religious Observance, 1 Oct. 1950 (Box 16)
  - 25th Anniversary - Resume of programs and clippings (Box 16)
  - 29th Anniversary (Box 16)
  - 30th Anniversary - Complete Program (Box 16)
  - 30th Anniversary - Virginia Cavalcade,Autumn 1955; Rough Draft of "Catwhiskers and Kilocycles" (Box 16)
  - 30th Anniversary - WRVA Milestones (chronology) (Box 16)